If we were to equate AI to launching
rockets,
data is the launch pad, right? You need
a good launching infrastructure to be in
place. Then you can launch as [music]
many rockets as you want. So the thing I
think a quote that I really like is
garbage in is garbage squared out. So So
uh just basically making sure you can
minimize [music] biases. Making sure
you're transparent and clear about what
data you have. The other piece of it is
we have to get our data thing right.
Right. We've kicked the Forgive me for
saying, but we've kicked the can down
the road too many times.
>> Oh, yeah.
>> Well, I have a special treat for you all
today. I am live on location at Planet
Hollywood in Las Vegas, Nevada for the
Put Data First Conference. And joining
me today on the signal room is a new
friend, uh, Amit Shivpuja. He currently
is a director of data and AI enablement
for Wallarch. And I'm really happy to be
able to get to meet you and to meet you
at such an important event where we're
here talking about AI. We're talking
about the currency of trust. We're
talking about the importance that
>> getting this foundation right, thinking
about it from an ethics and responsible
perspective is is really uh built into
the fabric of how how we're we're
designing everything. So you and I have
talked a little bit about this, you
know, from the topic that we want to
talk about. It's really the hidden
infrastructure of trust and you said you
can't scale AI without scaling trust.
tell me a little about what that means
to you and what does that look like in
practice?
>> Sure. And first, thank you so much for
having me and welcome the opportunity.
Um, so
>> if we were to equate AI to launching
rockets,
data is the launch pad, right? You need
a good launching infrastructure to be in
place. Then you can launch as many
rockets as you want.
>> So it's can't be heat sensitive. the
heat of [laughter]
>> well it depends how you define heat but
uh no uh the thing is that uh since AI
learn patterns from the data you want to
get that as right as possible in order
to minimize uh things uh further on in
the thing I think a quote that I really
like is garbage in is garbage squared
out so so uh just basically making sure
you can minimize biases making sure
you're transparent and clear about what
data you have,
>> right?
>> Uh making sure that there's
accountability because you don't want to
deploy something and then have people
come back and say what do we do now or
you know who's going to fix this? Uh
etc. So it's all of those layers coming
into play in order to make sure that the
output that gets generated is actually
trusted by the users. The thing with
especially today's generative AI and all
it's so easy to use and people tend to
put more trust in it because the
friction is so low and it's very easy to
lose that friction also because you know
if you keep giving wrong answers either
due to hallucinations or the training
data that was used. So you know building
that trust becomes extremely important.
So it's transparency, it's
accountability
and uh it's also showcasing how do you
get and where this came from. Right.
Right.
>> So yeah.
>> So it's an interesting concept when you
when you're talking about the building
the trust when you already got something
kind of in motion. But how do you think
about it um in terms of where you launch
from and at what point do you start
bringing in subject matter experts and
people who are actually on the front
line and might actually use it and how
important is that? I think you have to
start that very early on because a lot
of the context comes from them, right? I
I wish we were in a world where
everything was documented and all of
that which is not the case. But so even
the users, the subject matter experts,
you want to involve them as early as you
can. In fact, it's worthwhile actually
figuring out your requirements, your
exact needs and what business impact it
could potentially have even before you
go down building anything. So that way
you actually have some direction or some
baseline against which you want to
compare the outputs that you get
>> right. So them being part of the journey
is an extremely critical component as
early on as possible. And the other
benefit is that once you launch this
stuff they might become your biggest
champions in the organization helping
with adoption right and also figuring
out the road map into the future. Yeah,
I think that's a it's a really
interesting
point you're bringing up because I think
trust can be lost before you even start.
And I and I think it's re really
critical to understand that if you want
human beings to benefit and leverage
this capability, they have to believe in
it and they they're not going to believe
it if they don't understand the purpose
behind it and what it's intended to do.
Um
>> there's a there's a lot of change going
on. So
>> right, I know in healthcare, one of the
things that's always been problematic is
that uh we often tend to design
something first
>> and it's almost I call I I call it the
the field of dreams kind of approach. If
you build it, they will come. Well, if
we build something really cool and
exciting, someone will obviously need
it.
>> Uh but this is really not not always the
case.
>> Um talk about the sensitivity and the
fear piece of it if you wouldn't mind.
How do you get people comfortable to
actually highlight a workflow maybe that
would be a candidate for automation on
some level even if it's just basic
automation uh when they're also
balancing this fear that AI could take
their job.
>> Yeah. Um I mean what impact it'll have
from a job perspective is currently up
for debate right there's camps on either
side but uh I think to alleviate the
fear is like I said bringing them early
on in the conversation but it's also
showing them value
>> right let's say you know they're
spending 10 hours doing something
manually and it brings them down to 1
hour right so that kind of manual effort
which can introduce errors and all of
that gets reduced so it helps helps them
be more efficient. But also, I think
it's good to have a conversation on what
the rest the save time can be used for,
right? I'm sure they have things that
they want to improve. They have things
that they want to do or other challenges
that their teams need to address which
can now be focused on because you're
gaining those efficiencies and the time.
Uh now that also means that people have
to become some level of data literate
and AI literate, right? Because that's
the landscape, right? So the question
then becomes how do you support them?
How do you help them transition and pick
that up? Now everybody doesn't need to
know all the technical details but they
need to know at least a baseline of what
an LLM is, what it can do, what's an
agent and stuff like that. So I think
some of that time can be invested in
upskilling in learning as well so that
you know they're ready for the next
thing because you may not want to lose
that subject matter expertise uh as
well. So yeah, I think that combination
is what will work. I think you're
touching on something that I think
people really need to be much more
cognizant of. Um you can stay in the
place where you're fearful of course and
that's the natural tendency but the
reality is you have the ab you have the
time now to take advantage of learning
to use the capabilities for your own
benefit. And I think AI will replace
some jobs probably at some point, but
what AI is not going to do, it's not
going to replace people who are have
embraced AI and figuring out how to use
it to their advantage and to to be able
to contribute at a higher level. Now,
you mentioned something about saving
time, which I think is something I want
to pause on for a second and have you
talk a little bit about as a leader. Um
often times when some kind of a process
improvement is implemented there
>> there is an some sort of an order that
comes down from leadership around how
that time is to be used. What's your
advice to to leaders as they're think
leading through this kind of transition
around balancing hearing and listening
to the workforce that are closest to the
action versus maybe making some
uninformed dictator dictation of
instruction and how to do that.
>> So I think it's twofold. one I think as
people like us who are at the bridge
between leadership and the you know the
people actually doing the stuff it's
good to bring them together to kind of
showcase what if possible options are
but I think uh what's worked for us is
prioritizing based on business value or
business impact if uh what comes from
leadership we can showcase that business
impact and the need then that takes
priority but if we can make a case using
the feedback and you know the examples
that we have bottom up that I think
should take business priority for the
same right and and so it comes down to
business value right so and that there's
only four of them you can save time you
can save money you can make money or you
can mitigate risk
>> so it's just a question of bucketing it
into that and having that messaging
right so then it's neutral it's
transparent it you know you can have a
convers you can tie it to goals that the
organization has
>> etc right so that happens so but what I
found is a A lot of the top down stuff
is more in terms of hey, we need to
transition towards this or adopt this.
It's not so much do this,
>> right? That
well actually I want to talk about the
trust thing just a little bit more. So
trust is something that typically takes
time to build. Um as you're working
through something is is um I'll say
disruptive because it it tends to feel
that way, right? Um,
how do what are the early warning signs
that we should look for where maybe
trust is starting to erode a little bit?
I I'll tell you a little bit more about
what's behind that, but I'd love to hear
your thoughts.
>> I think uh some of it is just reactions
that you're getting, right? If you if
you're keeping stakeholders in the loop
frequently, you know, you build a
prototype, you get feedback and all
that. uh you just the signals you get in
terms of usage in terms of feedback the
quality of the feedback even if you get
if you release a first version and you
put it out there and see how it's
adopted I think those are all key
signals but I think as leaders if we
have the right relationships we'll we'll
get those signals as well right if they
trust you they'll be like hey I don't
want to do this kind of a thing right so
that perspective is also really valuable
so yeah I think it's being constantly in
contact with stakeholders and the
enablers too.
>> So you're you're suggesting it's not a
flyby activity.
>> No. Okay.
>> No. Because somebody has to support this
going forward.
>> That's right.
>> Especially something like an agent, it
will drift. It will do something it's
not supposed to do. What do you do in
that situation? It's not a fire and
forget kind of a thing, right? So yeah.
>> Yeah. So well, let me tell you a little
bit where that was coming from. So I
actually was in a had a conversation
with with a a clinical psychologist very
recently and we were talking about trust
and the erosion of it and I think
intuitively we kind of know that things
have shifted in society here in the US
in particular. Um but the numbers are
staggering in terms of how few people
actually trust some of the basic
institutions that they 20 years ago
you'd have said do you trust your
government people would have said yes
eight at least eight out of 10. Today
that's different. Um, you can say that
and apply it to almost any kind of uh,
societal um, role that someone plays,
whether it's clergy, law enforcement, or
whatever. It's kind of across the board.
But people not trusting their leadership
in in the organization that they work
for or not even trusting their
colleagues is something we have to be
cognizant of. And so I really love the
fact that you're you're bringing
everything back to this this human
relationship and the need for that
constant monitoring and the back and
forth opening open dialogue. Yeah.
>> So that we're we're really not missing
those.
>> Um as we're kind of being wrapping up
our time,
>> if you're going to advise an
organization, you can pick an it could
be healthcare, could be retail, any
organization. We're at this
really amazing pivot point where we're
talking about some disruption that's
probably what I don't know 10x 100x what
the internet was in the '9s. Um what are
some if you tell two or three things
that you you would encourage leaders to
be really mindful of and cognizant of as
they're trying to navigate and lead
their organizations forward through this
transition?
>> Uh one that comes to mind is just
building off the trust conversation we
have which is the trust but verify piece
of it, right? uh trust the technology,
trust the teams to deliver, but verify
whether it really does what it's
supposed to do, right? Uh it's really
key to do that, especially given the
amount of uh automated capabilities that
these tools have because unlike the
internet, AI is building the tool in
some cases. It's not AI doing something
quicker alone, right? So, it's got its
own capabilities. The other piece of it
is we have to get our data thing right.
Right. We've kicked the forgive me for
saying but we've kicked the can down the
road too many times and that foundation
even with getting even in a idealistic
scenario where we get the data right
we're still going to have biases we're
still going to have you know patterns
that occur because of the way the
business is set up or the data that's
collected and the like. So there's still
a lot of work that needs to be done but
if you don't do this then you can't do
that. The third I'd say is human in the
loop is non-negotiables.
That's important. I love that.
>> Uh uh just the fact that uh whether it's
verifying things, whether it's having
them involved in the thing, etc.
>> Uh I mean at least for some time we're
building these things for a human being.
>> Right.
>> Right. So somebody has to represent the
human beings in the
>> So the third thing I'd say is that Yeah.
>> Oh, that's outstanding. Well, if if
someone wants to get a hold of you that
they've heard you talking today and they
they want to have a engaging
conversation around what do they how do
they need to proceed with this AI
journey? How do we get in touch with
you?
>> Sure. The best is to get me on LinkedIn.
Uh so you'll find me on LinkedIn but uh
if people are interested in the my
thought and couple of other frameworks
that I use personally I put out a book
called the data and AI compass. It's
available on Amazon.
>> Excellent. uh and it's available both in
soft and in Kindle versions and uh
that's another thing and I also blog
quite often on my Substack which is data
compass.substack.com substack.com. So
that's the other way that you can
>> Fantastic. Well, I will make sure for my
listeners that all of these things are
available and they'll be uh on our site
and in the the show notes. Um I mean
it's been a pleasure speaking with you
today. I am excited about this event. I
think we're going to have some some more
fun.
>> It's already been a good start. So yes,
>> it has. Thanks again for being on the
sign. Appreciate you.
>> Appreciate it.
>> That's it for this episode of the
Signaroo. If today's conversation
sparked something in you, an idea, a
challenge, or a perspective worth
amplifying, I'd love to hear from you.
Message me on LinkedIn or visit
cigarroompodcast.com
to explore being a guest on an upcoming
episode. Until next time, stay tuned,
stay curious, and stay human.